Phone: (404) 655 - 8823

Email: John.farina0824@gmail.com

# John M. Farina

Clearance Level: TS/SCI Full Scope Poly

## **Summary of Qualifications**

Student at the University of North Georgia, graduating in May of 2019 with a B.S. in Computer Science and a Concentration in Information Assurance and Security. Professional Experience in the fields of Information Security, Signals Intelligence, Data Analysis, Engineering, and Information Technology. Extensive knowledge and experience in a full spectrum of tools, databases, and computer applications as well as programming experience in Python, Java, C++, C#, XML, Swift, and SQL.

# **Professional Experience**

#### **Signals Intelligence Analyst**

#### National Security Agency – May 2018 to August 2018

Summer Intern Program for Information Assurance (SIP/IA) Participant

- Applied computer-based programs and various programming languages (Python, C++, etc.) to process data for analytical problems.
- Tracked cyber activity by looking for patterns, networking techniques, and protocols being used.
- Added, updated, or enriched information in mission-relevant databases.
- Conducted target analysis, target research, and analysis of metadata.
- Identified target communications within the global network.
- Selected, built, and developed query strategies against appropriate collection databases.

#### **Data Analyst**

## Elringklinger USA – October 2017 to May 2018

- Organized and sorted through the downtimes of various machines while calculating a total monetary value lost during this
  time.
- Designed and created forms/Excel sheets that displayed and calculated the downtimes of numerous machines.
- Developed solutions to lower downtime rates, by identifying the variables that were affecting the rate of production and proposed possible solutions to upper management.

#### **Engineering Specialist**

#### Elringklinger USA – May 2016 to September 2017

- Supervised Red Books (press setup/tooling instructions) to ensure updates and changes were made, when necessary.
- Used computer aided design software (AutoCAD and Solidworks) to produce revised layouts of portions of the production floor and designed numerous mechanical parts.
- Performed multiple capability studies on parts in production, in order to test the integrity of the part in question.
- Built fixtures to increase productivity and safety.
- Worked with upper management to begin the implementation of the 5S principles and the S.M.E.D. process throughout the plant.

#### Race Relay Manager/IT Specialist

## Toccoa Raceway – March 2015 to September 2017

- Scored weekly Saturday night races via Race Manager (scoring software), while simultaneously running a live feed of times and positions to the Race Monitor mobile application.
- Supervised website and social media traffic/content.
- Aided with computer and printer complications, while ensuring that all applications and hardware are up-to-date.

#### **Education**

B.S. Computer Science, University of North Georgia – May 2019

Concentration in Information Assurance and Security

A.S. Computer Science, University of North Georgia - May 2017

# **Training**

Programming Languages: Java, Python, C++, C#, Swift, XML, SQL, HTML/CSS

Software Development Course, University of North Georgia

- Software Engineering
- Data Structures & Analysis of Algorithms
- Programming Languages
- Mobile Application Development
- Artificial Intelligence

# Information Security Courses, University of North Georgia

- Computer Forensics
- Network Security
- Computer Security
- Information Security
- Management of Information Security
- Reverse Engineering

efe		

Christine Garner	(678) $936 - 3459$
Michael Stells	(678) 725 – 2841
(Doctor) Redahegn Sileshi	(678) 717 – 3599
(Doctor) Sudhanshu Panda	(678) 507 – 4033
(Professor) Dale Crandall	(678) 717 – 3827
(Doctor) Irfan Bagci	(678) 717 – 3944
(Doctor) Bryson Payne	. (678) 717 – 3599

**Additional Resources** 

• GitHub: github.com/JFarina5